As far as I can remember,
I've never done anything that would
make humans want to slay me.
At times, I've even been their ally.
Perhaps there are things that bind you...
No excuses, then?
Very well.
I've lived a little too long...
Perhaps it's a less than fitting
end for an ancient, divine dragon
that's been alive since the age of gods...
But maybe the world can have one
dragon meet its end like this.
Oh, grim reapers, take my
soul to the underworld,
so that I may rest eternally...
He's been born? You did it, Arsena!
Shut up! You shouldn't be
that loud around the mother!
Look, his eyes are open already!
Amazing! Perhaps he's gifted in some manner!
Well, he's my son, after all!
Hello, my baby. Your name is Dolan.
I'm your mom, and this is your dad.
And this is your big brother.
Dolan, let's go home!
What's wrong, Dolan?
It's nothing, Airi.
Come on, let's go.
Goodbye, Dragon Life
Verun, a small village on the north border
of the continental kingdom of Arcrest.
After I died as a dragon, by some strange
fate I was born here, as a human.
The only industry here is agriculture.
Every day I go out into the fields and
work hard to earn my daily bread.
In the village,
you're considered an adult at age 15,
and you're expected to live on your own.
I'm 16 now, so I left my home
last year and now I live alone.
Hey, Dolan. Tomorrow's the day you're
going to investigate that swamp, right?
Yeah.
It's been a month since the lizards
disappeared from the swamp.
We have to do something.
That's supposed to be the garrison's job.
There's no reason for you to go.
Brother, Captain Balan and the others have
their hands full guarding the village.
You sure you don't want me to go with you?
Don't worry. I'm fine.
I'm just going to check it out—
There it is!
It's a big one!
Hey, Dolan. Big catch today.
Right?
This looks like quite a big meal.
Shouldn't you be preparing
for tomorrow, though?
I've been preparing little by
little for the past several days.
You helped me a lot by persuading
the village chief and the others.
Well, you always help me with our training.
Malida, Albert, are the
two of you heading out?
Yes, we have a meeting about the next
training session for the little ones.
Don't worry about us.
Prioritize your investigation tomorrow.
Thanks.
There are a lot of monsters
around Verun, as well as bandits.
And there aren't enough soldiers to give
the protection you'd find in a city.
The villagers are expected
to help protect themselves.
Dolan, it's magic practice
day. Did you remember?
Hey, Airi.
Is it that time already?
Did you come to get me?
I was out on an errand already.
Laws of power, hear my voice.
Become an arrow and pierce my foe.
Energy bolt!
Wow!
Yes, as always,
your offensive magic is perfect.
It's thanks to your teachings.
Now we'll practice magical
medicines, your worst subject.
We'll spend a lot of time on it.
Thank you, ma'am.
Dolan, allow me to introduce you.
Chief?
This is Christina.
She'll be staying in our
village for a while.
She's a young noble lady.
Be on your best behavior.
I'm Christina. Nice to meet you.
I'm Dolan.
Christina, was it?
She seems quite skilled...
In the village, you risk
freezing to death in winter,
and it's incredibly hot in summer.
I was shocked to find out humans
lived in such a harsh environment.
Oh, Brother Dolan!
Marco.
You're back, huh?
Welcome back.
I'm back.
I brought you this.
Wow, look at it all.
Thank you.
Your cooking is always the best, Mom.
Dolan, living on your own may be
relaxing, but you must be lonely.
Why not get a wife who's a
good cook, like Dylan did?
Brother says the same thing sometimes.
But I think I want to enjoy the single
life for a little while longer.
You're going to that
swamp tomorrow, right?
Yeah, the one where the
lizards used to live.
It's a long ways away,
and isn't the road dangerous?
I won't be taking risks.
I'm just going to get near it
and look at the swamp.
Really?
Yeah.
You're an adult now, so it's
your decision to make.
Do as you like.
But come back safe so
your mom doesn't worry.
That's all I have to say.
Thanks, Dad.
Don't worry, I'm sure I'll
have a great story to tell.
This is a bit too much, isn't it?
Nonsense!
This is supposed to be
a job for us soldiers!
I think I'll go after all...
Don't be stupid.
What if monsters attack
while you're gone, Captain?
Let me give you a simple goddess's blessing.
Thank you, Letisha.
Dolan, I don't want to scare you,
but my fortune-telling is showing
the tiniest hint of something bad.
Be careful.
Yes, ma'am.
Um, I made you lunch.
Eat it on the road.
Sure. Thanks, Airi.
Bye! Take care!
The lizards in the swamp would occasionally
interact with Verun village.
But one day they just disappeared.
Since we couldn't just do nothing,
I volunteered to investigate what happened.
Now, what am I going to find...?
So this is the place...
I see.
This explains why the
lizards can't live here.
The earth elementals' power is too strong
and the water elementals' power is weakening.
Old Lady Maguru's fortune-telling
is usually right.
Something's there.
Only a powerful monster could
live in this swamp currently.
Y-You came here alone...
Foolish human.
A lamia, huh?
You don't usually see them around here...
Though I see... She's as
beautiful as the rumors say...
Are you all alone, by the way?
It's just me.
Nobody else is here.
W-Whew! I'm glad.
Um, what should I do?
I think I'm supposed to use charm
and then do those movements mom
taught me over and over again...
What are those strange movements?
Human! I did not come to fight!
Let's get out of here!
Wh-What is that thing?
It's okay now.
Just what is that thing?
It's a mad earth elemental.
An elemental? I've never seen one like that.
There used to be lizards who lived
here, but they all vanished one day.
That thing is probably why.
I heard there was a big
earthquake a while back.
That probably affected the elemental.
Unfortunately, it won't go back to normal.
I'm Dolan.
What's your name?
I'm Celina.
I've heard all lamias
can use magic. Can you?
Oh... Yes, I can.
Okay.
I have a suggestion.
Why don't we fight it together?
But! But! Lamia are earth monsters,
so I don't think I can...
So your magic can't really damage it, huh?
But, well...
I think the lamia's unique racial spell
will work on an earth elemental...
Okay.
How about this? I'll go out in
front and you can back me up.
O-Okay.
In sickness and in health,
till death do us part...
Isn't that what you say
when you get married?
Sorry!
I just met this human... I don't know
if I can work together with him.
That's the signal.
Accursed demon snake that flows within me...
Come forth and curse my foe!
Jaraam!
Indeed.
No, it can't hold it...
That's plenty.
If I imbue my sword with draconic magic...
You did it!
I'm all muddy!
You okay?
It got in my mouth, too.
Indeed. You don't seem hurt.
Thanks for helping.
Allow me to introduce myself properly.
I'm Dolan from Verun village.
I'm Celina.
As you can see, I'm a lamia.
Celina? Yes, that's a good name.
First, we need to clean you
up and dry your clothes.
You must be cold.
Y-Yes.
You're not scared of me
at all, are you, Dolan?
Yes.
You seem different from the lamias I know.
What kind do you know?
They're more wary of humans,
and more aggressive, I guess...
There aren't any lamia villages around here.
What are you doing here?
When a lamia turns 17,
there's a rule that says they
have to leave to find a husband.
And that's what you're doing?
Yes. In accordance with that rule,
I'm going on a journey to find a husband.
Oh, that's wonderful.
Lamia are an all-female race,
so we only give birth to girls.
Very rarely, we'll give birth to a boy,
but it's always of our husbands' race.
Lamia are a race that were created
when a female human was cursed.
That curse was passed down.
We're partially snakes, and our
body fluids contain poison.
So we need to choose a husband who's got
a strong body and is resistant to poison.
Otherwise, you see...
Um... when we k-kiss... or m-make babies...
the man will die from poison!
I see. So it's harder to find a partner
for you than it is for other races.
My mom met my dad on a journey, too!
He was a human, just like you!
They get along great!
That's a good thing.
A-Are you treating me like a child?
Not at all...
I was just thinking you're
a very cute lamia.
C-Cute?
You are treating me like a child!
Don't get so upset.
Here.
I'm not as good a cook as my mom,
but I think this is pretty tasty.
It's wonderful.
What is it? I've never had it before.
It smells good and it's really rich!
Is it made with milk?
Sorry... I got excited.
I'm glad you liked it.
My mom taught me how to make it.
On cold winter nights, we all
gathered around the pot to eat it.
You have such a kind smile when
you talk about your family.
You love your family, don't you?
Oh, right.
The dragon in the cave who
was all alone is gone now...
Dolan?
Is something wrong?
No, I was just thinking that you're right.
I love my family.
So do I!
I'm sure you'll find a great partner.
Thanks.
Hm... I've heard lamias like life energy.
Sorry, did I scare you?
Hmm. Perhaps a dragon's life
energy was too strong...
Anyway, I'm going back to my village.
I'm going to head south and
keep looking for a husband.
When your journey's over,
come by my village with your husband.
I'll introduce my family.
Okay! I definitely will!
May the path you walk be a blessed one.
You too, Dolan. Be well!
Next Episode
This week's lucky item is spirit crystals!
Look forward to next time!